Textures.
次はテクスチャをみていきます。
A texture is an image file.
テクスチャは画像ファイルであり、
Unity uses textures in a number of different ways.
Unity はテクスチャをさまざまな方法で使用します。
The most common use of a texture is when
もっとも一般的なテクスチャの使用方法は
applied to a material in the base
マテリアルのベース テクスチャ プロパティに適用して
texture property to give a mesh a
メッシュの表面に
textured surface.
テクスチャつきの表面を与えます。
For more information on materials
マテリアルに関する情報については
see the appropriate lesson.
対応するレッスンを参照して下さい。
Textures can also be used for
テクスチャはさらに
GUI elements applied to additional
GUI 要素は追加のマテリアル
material properties to act as normal
プロパティに適用して、法線マップ、
maps, specular maps or height maps.
鏡面マップ、またはハイトマップとして使用できます。
Used as custom cursors, icons,
カスタムのカーソル、アイコン、
splash screens and more.
スプラッシュ画面、などにも使用できます。
Textures can be any image file
テクスチャは
supported by Unity.
Unity でサポートされる画像であれば何でも問題ありません。
These can be photos straight from a
これらは 電子コンテンツ からダイレクトの写真に出来ますが、
digital source, but textures are usually
テクスチャは 通常、
images created or manipulated in an image
Photoshop または Gimp のようなイメージ エディタにより
editor, like Photoshop or Gimp.
作成されます。
It is important to note that the layered
レイヤーのあるファイルは
files will be flattened on import
インポート時にフラットになりますが、
but the layers are maintained in
レイヤーは Unity 上のオリジナル ファイルでは
Unity in the original file.
保持されています。
This means we can turn layers on and off
これはつまりレイヤーをロスなく
without loss when we're setting up our game
オンにしたり、オフにしたり出来るということですが、
but when we're running our game we will not
ゲームを実行するときは
have access to these layers individually.
これらのレイヤーに個別にアクセス出来ないということです。
Most of the image file formats used by
Unity により使用される画像形式のほとんどで
Unity support transparency.
Unity は透過設定をサポートします。
The notable exception is JPEG,
覚えておくべき例外は JPEG であり、
which does not.
これはサポートしてません。
For more information on transparency
透過設定についてのより詳細な情報と
and how to use it, see the documentation on
使用方法については、
materials and shaders.
マテリアルやシェーダーに関するドキュメントを参照して下さい。
Texture files should be saved in the assets folder.
テクスチャ ファイルは Assets フォルダに保存すべきです。
Unity searches the assets folder
Unity は マテリアルを検索するとき
in a specific order when seeking materials.
Assets フォルダを特定の順番で検索します。
For more information on searching for textures
テクスチャの検索および
and seeking materials see the lesson
マテリアルの検索についての詳細は
on mesh importing.
メッシュのインポートに関するレッスンを参照して下さい。
A texture file should be assigned import
テクスチャ ファイルは
settings in the texture importer.
テクスチャ インポート ツールによりインポート設定が割り当てられます。
Texture Type property contains a
Texture Type プロパティには
list of presets.
プリセットの一覧が含まれます。
These limit the number of editable properties
これらによりテクスチャ インポート ツールにより
available in the texture importer
画像の使用方法に関連して意図的に
based on the intended use for the image.
編集出来るプロパティの数を限定します。
The default is Texture.
デフォルトの値は Texture です。
Advanced will expose all of the available
Advanced とするとテクスチャ インポート ツールで
properties in the texture importer.
利用出来るプロパティの全てが使えるようになります。
The other presets, including advanced,
その他のプリセットは Advanced を含めて
will be covered in another lesson.
別のレッスンでカバーします。
If we need to set the transparency
もし テクスチャの
or alpha channel for the texture automatically
透過またはアルファ チャネルを画像の
based on the light and dark parts of the image
明暗にもとづいて自動的にセットしないといけない場合、
we can check the Alpha From Greyscale field.
Alpha From Greyscale フィールドをチェックします。
Black will be completely transparent,
黒色は完全に透過となり、
white will be completely opaque.
白色は完全に不透明になります。
Wrap Mode controls how the texture is mapped
Wrap Mode によりテクスチャがタイルされたときに
on to a renderer when tiled.
レンダラにどうマッピングするか制御します。
This setting works for both 2D elements
この設定は 2D 要素でも
and 3D meshes.
3D メッシュでも機能します。
Repeat will repeat the texture and
Repeat によりテクスチャは繰り返しされ
and Clamp will stretch the edges of the texture.
Clamp によりテクスチャの端が伸ばされます。
Filter Mode controls how the graphics
Filter Mode により グラフィックス カードが
card renders the texture,
3D 変形により伸ばされたとき、
when it is stretched by 3D transformations.
テクスチャをどうレンダリングするか制御します。
These are effectively quality settings,
これらは要するに Quality Settings であり、
trilinear being the best and
Trilinear が最も高画質であり、
point being the most basic.
Point は最も標準的となります。
Aniso level controls the quality of
Aniso level により テクスチャの
textures when rendered at steep angles.
深い角度でレンダリングされたときの品質が制御されます。
Anisotropic Filtering increases the
Anisotropic Filtering により、
texture quality when viewed at
見上げる角度で見たときの
a grazing angle.
テクスチャ品質を向上します。
This has an increased rendering cost when applied.
これは適用したときにレンダリング コストを向上させます。
In quality settings, Anisotropic filtering
Quality Settings においては、Anisotropic Filteringによって
can be forced on for all textures
全てのテクスチャを強制的にオンにしたり、
or disabled completely.
完全にオフにすることが出来ます。
For more information on quality settings
Quality Settings に関する詳細については
see the appropriate lesson.
対応するレッスンを参照して下さい。
Because Unity supports building to
Unity によりマルチ ターゲットの
multiple target platforms from one project
プラットフォームへのビルドをサポートするので
the texture importer allows for a default
テクスチャ インポート ツールは
setting for max texture size
最大テキスト サイズ
and compression format that can be
および圧縮フォーマットにデフォルト設定をして
overridden on a per platform basis.
プラットフォーム毎にそれを上書きすることが出来ます。
Max Size will set the maximum size for
Max Size によりインポートされたテクスチャの最大サイズを
for the imported texture.
セット出来ます。
If max size is set to a value larger
もし Max Size が
than that of the original image the size
元の画像よりも大きい値にセットした場合、
of the imported texture
インポートされたテクスチャのサイズは
will be that of the original.
は元の画像のサイズどおりになります。
This setting will not make the texture
この設定により元の画像よりも大きい
larger than the original image.
テクスチャとはなりません。
If max size is set to a value less
もし Max Size が
than the original image the texture will
元の画像よりも小さい値にセットした場合、
be resized to that value on import.
インポートされたときに、テクスチャのサイズは Max Size どおりになります。
Like layers, however, the original
しかし、レイヤーと同様に、
file is unchanged.
元の画像は変更されていません。
Only the imported asset will be adjusted.
インポートされたアセットのみが調整されています。
Format sets the compression technique.
Format により圧縮方式がセットされます。
The default settings are relatively simple
デフォルト設定は Texture プリセットを使用すると
when using the Texture preset.
比較的シンプルです。
These are effectively quality settings of
これは要するに Low, Medium, High の
low, medium and high.
画質設定となります。
More control can be set on a per
プラットフォームごとにより多くの制御を
platform basis, or when using the Advanced setting.
することが出来ます。または Advanced 設定を使用する場合も同様です。
Each target platform can have it's own settings
各々のターゲット プラットフォームには
that override the default values.
デフォルト値を上書きする自身の設定があります。
Max size and compression can be adjusted
Max size および Compression は各々のターゲット プラットフォームで
for each target platform.
調整できます。
This means we can set the target sizes
これはつまり、ターゲット プラットフォームの
and compression appropriate for the
帯域およびプロセッシング能力にあわせて
bandwidth and processing power
ターゲット サイズおよび圧縮
of the target platform.
セットできます。
When the build target is changed these
ビルド ターゲットが変更されたとき、
assets will be reimported using the
これらのアセットは上書きされた値を使用して
overridden values.
再インポートされます。
This section works in conjunction with Build Settings.
このセクションでは Build Settings で作業をします。
For more information on Build Settings
Build Settings に関する詳細については
please see the appropriate lesson.
対応するレッスンを参照して下さい。
At the bottom of the importer is a preview window.
インポート ツールの最下部にはプレビュー ウィンドウがあります。
When the preview window is open we can
もしプレビュー ウィンドウが開いているとき
view the changes we have made.
われわれが行なった変更をみることが出来ます。
We will need to apply our settings before
プレビュー ウィンドウが表示を更新する前に
the preview window will update it's display.
設定を適用する必要があります。
The preview window will display the image
プレビュー ウィンドウはインポートされる画像を表示して
being imported and report basic information
インポートされたテクスチャに関する
about the imported texture, including
基本的な情報を報告します。
the size of the imported texture,
それはインポートされたテクスチャ サイズ、
the compression setting and the footprint
圧縮設定、およびテクスチャのフットプリントを
of the texture in our game.
含みます。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)